# Rowan Carmichael

### Frontend Engineer

$oxed{\square}$	carmichaelr@hotmail.co.uk	in	linkedin.com/in/rowan-carmichael
	+64210794594	0	github.com/RowanCarmichael
0	Relocating to Melbourne, Australia		rowancarmichael.github.io/site

Skilled frontend engineer with a passion for creating innovative React applications. Confident communicator and critical thinker with an inquisitive personality. Has ample experience developing customer focused solutions with the best usability experience in mind. Thoroughly enjoys the challenge of solving new problems and is highly motivated to learn and grow. Well versed in both Scrum and Kanban agile development methodologies within a high performing team environment. Takes great pride in code quality, understanding the importance of creating automated tests spanning all levels of the testing pyramid to ensure the highest quality of products are released.

# **SKILLS**

Experienced In:	Familiar With:	
ReactJS	SQL	
JavaScript	Java	
HTML	C#	
CSS	Xamarin	

## FAVOURITE FRAMEWORKS

Redux	Mobx	CSS Modules	Eslint
Chai	Enzyme	Mocha	Selenium
Flow	Babel	Webpack	Node.js (Express)

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **React Frontend Engineer**

EROAD Limited February 2016 – Ongoing

Tasked with leading, co-developing and maintaining the frontend for five new SaaS projects related to driver health & safety, reports/auditing, and vehicle maintenance/compliance

After completing the first major React project in the mobile team; personally received the EROAD 2017 CEO Award and helped the team achieve the EROAD Q1 2017 and the Q4 2017 Engineering Team Awards

Taught/mentored four developers learning React and organised several workshop presentations defining development best-practices and standards for React frontend across the company

Created and maintained unit, component, UI and end-to-end level tests for all frontend code I wrote which helped our team consistently have the lowest bug rate out of all product-based development teams in the company

Worked closely with backend developers, UI/UX designers, product managers and testers in an agile development environment utilising both Scrum and Kanban methodologies

#### **Web Developer**

**Opus International Consultants Limited** 

March 2015 - November 2015

Worked part-time in a team of three developers, creating a real-time mobile web app hazard management system as a university industry project

#### **Computer Science Lab Demonstrator**

University of Auckland Computer Science Department

March 2015 - November 2015

Assisted undergraduate students with computer science related questions for practical assignments and tutorials

# **EDUCATION**

### **BTech(Hons) Specialising in Information Technology**

University of Auckland

March 2012 - November 2015

# **HOBBIES / INTERESTS**

I enjoy living a balanced lifestyle striving for a wholesome mental and physical wellbeing. I do my best to keep active playing competitive ultimate frisbee (up to the national level), yoga, gymming and walking wherever I can. To relax and unwind I like to play piano, cook, and I am an avid gamer (both PC and board games - my favourite being strategy games)